You are trying to log in to a website. The domain
looks good - you opened it like you always do.
You think you typed your password correctly, but
the app tells you didn't it so you retype it again
- it happens. But little do you know that by doing
that you just gave your passwords to the attacker.
Hello, the vulnerability I will show today is the
most fun and creative exploit I have ever done
for bug bounty. I chained SSRF with phishing,
which doesn't really sound familiar, does it?
Unfortunately, even though I'm very happy with
this bug, I still didn't make the most out of
it and learned the lesson the hard way. But for
now, enjoy the explanation! I found this bug in
the private program. Let's say it's redacted.com.
There is a way to set up two factor authentication
via Duo. The way it works is you create an
account on Duo. It generates credentials for
you and assigns a subdomain that looks
like this: api-random.duosecurity.com.
To set it up on redacted.com, you copy these
credentials and the hostname. Then, redacted
does the validation. It checks if the host starts
with api- and ends with .duosecurity.com. And
these validations are robust. If you do them on
the host. But redacted.com did not. It didn't
normalize the address and these validations were
run on your whole input, not just on the host.
So it's quite easy. You can use this address to
bypass it while still controlling the hostname.
And after the validation, redacted.com makes
a request to auth/v2/check endpoint. It just
concatenates your host to this path and this is
the final location where your request is sent.
This way you can trick the server into sending
requests to an arbitrary location. It's a typical
server-side request forgery. As you could
not read the response, it's a blind one.
And of course, after this request, redacted threw
an error because my service was not responding to
this request with the expected format. But since
it's a blind SSRF anyway, it doesn't really
matter - the request was already sent. Usually,
to elevate the impact of a blind SSRF, you need
to find another service in the internal network
which you can exploit with a single request.
So the impact of this bug varies a lot. But
redacted is an open-source application which you
can install yourself. So impact here is greater
because, you know, the company can say "we don't
have any internal services that can be chained
with a blind SSRF", but they can't say "none of
our clients has services in the internal network
that could be chained with it". So I reported the
blind SSRF and went to sleep as it was quite late
and I'm not a night owl. But remember I told you
earlier there was an error due to my server not
responding with the expected format? When I was
falling asleep, I was wondering what would happen
if my server would return a proper response,
just like a real Duo API server would. Maybe I
even dreamt about it, but I don't remember that.
So the next morning, I came back to it. I thought
that maybe if I managed to set up the integration
with my server, something interesting will be sent
to me during the logging process. So I created a
Duo account and used real credentials. And this
is the response that my proof of concept server
had to return. And it worked! I successfully
added two-factor authentication with my server
and the way the Duo integration works is that
after the login, the iframe from my subdomain
is opened with the input field where you
fill in the OTP code that you received
via a text message from Duo. So when I was
trying to log in, the server tried to open
an iframe from my own server. It was a perfect
attack scenario. I created a proof of concept
that looked like redacted.com's login page.
And after the login, my form was shown in the
victim's browser. It looked exactly like the one
from redacted.com... minus my HTML/CSS skills.
The domain of the iframe is not visible to the
victim, so this is pretty much perfect phishing.
In a real word attack, I could also add
the message about an invalid password.
It's because the victim is taken to my
iframe after a successful login. I would
show them an alert about an invalid
password so that they retype it again.
But the question you might be asking yourself
is what is the impact of phishing myself? The
thing is that redacted.com also has teams and as
the admin of the team, I can set up two-factor
authentication for all members. And with this
attack, I can get their plaintext passwords.
This, however, makes the attack less likely.
So even though the attack is super cool,
is not as impactful. And this is a place I find
myself quite often when doing bug bounty. I have
like a childish curiosity - I just want to break
things and not care about the impact. I'm not sure
if that's a good thing because not always cool
attacks result in equally great impact. And I feel
that if I want to get maximum return on investment
from doing bug bounty, I should focus on things
that are the most impactful and not necessarily
the coolest. But on the other hand, in some
situations that curiosity is definitely helping me
out. This attack gave me so much satisfaction. So
I added the comment to the original report. One
problem was that the CSP didn't allow opening
iframes from my domain. It reminded me of my
recent endeavours with the content security
policy on Stripe. I didn't initially report my 2
XSSes because of the CSP. Later, turned out they
rewarded me for them very well, treating CSP
only as a defence in-depth mechanism. So here,
I didn't consider turning off CSP a big problem.
But this program had a different attitude.
They only rewarded me $500 which looked like a
reward that didn't consider the phishing attack
scenario - only the blind SSRF. So I replied
to them, saying why I think I should get more.
I mentioned a possible bypass of the first
fix and explained this second attack scenario.
But unfortunately, by doing it, I spoiled
it and I'm still angry with myself for that.
I thought about bypassing
the content security policy,
but it's an iframe and I only controlled the host,
so I couldn't think of anything worth trying here.
And for my augmentation, they gave me $500 more.
And initially, I was very happy with that reward.
But after a few days, when the bug
was fixed and the report was closed,
I logged in to redacted.com. But this
time not via the website, but with an app
and to my eyes, my phishing page popped up
without turning off the content security policy.
Turned out that my phishing exploit was complete,
just via another login channel. And in case of
this app, I think it may be a more popular
way to log in than the website itself. So
I didn't know how much more they would
be willing to pay me, but definitely
something more. But after already arguing one
time, I didn't want to do it the second time
since the report was already closed. And
I'm still angry with myself for that.
It's a hard way to learn to always,
always check different channels.
But even though I didn't mention it in the report,
I know that my proof of concept was complete
and this was the coolest exploit I have
ever done, at least so far. And after all,
$1,000 is not bad, especially since found it
after just starting hunting on the program.
With this money, I'm fulfilling one of
my dreams to go to an F1 race. In fact,
right now, as this video is published, I'm in
Barcelona on Spanish Formula One Grand Prix.
Less than a year ago I was a pentester
and even though I had web security skills,
I just couldn't find bugs in bug bounty. I was
learning a lot and I hoped that it will finally
yield results. Albeit bug bounty is not easy and
definitely not a get rich quick scheme, I can see
that all this learning pays off and I'm finding
cool bugs that enable me to fulfil my dreams.
If you want to learn with me,
subscribe to BBRE Premium.
I'm documenting things that I learn there. What
tools do I use, what methodology, what hacking
techniques. It's all about continuous learning
of intermediate and advanced level topics.
Check out bbre.dev/premium. For now,
thank you for watching and goodbye!